A Guide to the B. DeRoy Beale Genealogical research files, ca. 1980-2007
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
B. DeRoy Beale Genealogical research files, ca. 1980-2007
The Library of Virginia
43433
7.75 cu. ft. (21 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of B. DeRoy Beale, August 2007.
Biographical Information
Barkley DeRoy Beale and his twin, Thornton LeRoy Beale, were born April 1924 to Charlie Joel Beale (1876-1958) and Anna Lee Owen (1881-1936) of Halifax County, Virginia. They trace their family lines back to Shadrack Beal (ca. 1765-1815) of Pittsylvania County and Captain Robert Tucker Sr. (ca. 1677-1750) of Prince George County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Genealogical research files, ca. 1980-2007, of B. DeRoy Beale, including family research files and county research notes. Contains extensive information on the Beale, Blanks, Clements, Ferguson, Owen, Tucker, and related families of Amelia, Charles City, Halifax, Lunenburg, Mecklenburg, Pittsylvania and Prince George Counties, Virginia. Also includes correspondence with genealogical researchers relating to The Beale Family of Halifax County, Virginia and Tucker Trails Through Southside Virginia by B. DeRoy Beale. Every effort was made during processing of the collection to maintain the original order of the materials. In some cases information can be found in several different series, therefore cross-checking of all series is suggested.
Also included are oversize genealogical charts and a CD-ROM with the Beale family Personal Ancestral files. (located in Series II)
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Tucker family and Tucker Trails Through Southside Virginia
Series II: Beale and related family files
Series III: Miscellaneous family files
Series IV: County research files
Contents List
- Series I: Tucker family and Tucker Trails Through Southside Virginia, Extent: 2.9 cu. ft. (9 boxes) (Box 1-9)
  This series includes correspondence to B. DeRoy Beale regarding the purchase of his book entitled, Tucker Trails Through Southside Virginia, and related questions to the genealogy of the Tucker family of Amelia, Charles City, Halifax, Lunenburg, Mecklenburg, Nottoway, Pittsylvania, Prince Edward, and Prince George Counties, Virginia.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name.
  - A - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aasby, Berta (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B - General (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - B - General (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bell, Mary Campbell (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blue Ridge Express (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Boisseau, Mary Leigh (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Burris, Pattie Tucker (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - C - General (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - C - General (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Campbell, Clarence H. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Capital PAF User Group (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chiarito, Marian (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cochran, Emmett Tucker (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - D - General (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - D - General (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - E - General (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - F - General (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - F - General (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - G - General (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gish, David (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gish, David (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - H - General (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - H - General (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I - General (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - J - General (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - K - General (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Knight, E.V. (Box 4, Folder 3a)
  - L - General (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - L - General (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mc - General (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - McCormack, Joseph (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - M - General (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - M - General (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - N - General (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - O - General (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - P - General (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - R - General (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - R - General (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - R - General (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - S - General (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - S - General (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - T - General (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Tucker, Douglas (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Tucker, Douglas (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Tucker, Douglas (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Tucker, George (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tucker, Joseph (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Tucker, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tucker, Norma (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tucker, William (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tucker, A-M (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tucker, A-M (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tucker, A-M (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tucker, N-Z (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Tucker, N-Z (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Tucker, N-Z (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Tucker email (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - U - General (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - W - General (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - X, Y, Z - General (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Articles, reviews, etc. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series II: Beale and related family files, Extent: 2.55 cu. ft. (7 boxes). (Box 9-15)
  This series includes clippings, correspondence, family group sheets, and genealogical notes and charts on the Beale and related families. Families researched are from all over Virginia, but there is a particular emphasis on those from Halifax and Pittsylvania Counties, Virginia. The files contain genealogical notes abstracted from court records, including deed books, order books, will books and marriage records. There is substantial information on the Beale and related Bass, Barley, Bell, Blanks, Clements, Davis, Epperson, Farris, Ferguson, Foster, Godby, Hubbard, Lacy, Owen, and Tucker families.
  Arranged alphabetically by family name.
  - Bass family (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Barley family (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Beale family reunion, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Beale, David (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Beale family (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Beale family (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Beale family (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Beale family (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Beale family CD-ROM (PAF) (Box 10, Folder 2a)
  - Beall Family Association (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bell Family Association (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Blanks family (Box 10, Folder 5-8)
  - Blanks, William L. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Clements - Clemons family (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Clements family (Box 11, Folder 2-6)
  - Clements, Edward (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Clements family (Mabel Clements Lecornu) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Clements family (Roger Clements Dodson) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Clements family (Roger Clements Dodson) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Clemons family (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Clemons, Marna (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Davis family (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Epperson family (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - Farris family (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Farris, Randall L. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ferguson family (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Foster family (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Godby family (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hubbard family (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lacy family (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Owen family (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Owen family (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
  - Owen family (Chapters) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Owen family (Patricia Albert) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Owen Family Association (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Owen Family Association (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Owen and Blanks family (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Owens-Clements book (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Owen Source Book One (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Virginia Family of John Owen (1676-1767) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Tucker family group sheets (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Series III: Miscellaneous family files, Extent: .90 cu. ft. (3 boxes). (Box 16-18)
  This series also includes correspondence, family group sheets, genealogical notes and charts, on the Appling, Bales, Bass, Beale, Booker, Carr, Clay, Davis, Faris, Ferguson, Ferrell, Hutcherson, Mayhew, Rucker, Toombs, and Tucker families of Virginia.
  - Appling family (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Appling-Lacy family (Box 16, Folder 1a)
  - Bales family (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Bass family (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Beal, John (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Beale, Thomas J. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Booker family (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Carr family (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Clay family (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Davis family (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Faris family (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Ferguson family (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Ferrell family (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Hutcherson family (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Mayhew family (Box 17, Folder 1a)
  - Mayhue family (Box 17, Folder 1b)
  - Rucker family (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Toombs family (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Tucker family (Box 17, Folder 4-9)
  - Tucker, Faye (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Tucker (Martha Tucker Bass) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Tucker, Robert (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Tucker, Robert (ca. 1677-1750) and James Tucker Sr. (ca. 1698-1773) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Foust-Grubb-Yeatts-Short-Tucker families (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Other Tuckers (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series IV: County research files., Extent: 1.4 cu. ft. (4 boxes). (Box 18-21)
  This series include abstracts from court records, as well as correspondence, clippings, tombstone inscriptions, pedigree charts and published works.
  - Amelia County, Va. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Amelia County, Va. Tithables (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Amherst County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Augusta County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bristol Parish register (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Brunswick County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Charles City County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Charlotte County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Chesterfield County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Dinwiddie County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Halifax County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Halifax County, Va. (Shadrack Beale) (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Halifax County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Halifax County, Va. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Henrico County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Henry County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Lunenburg County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Mecklenburg County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Nottoway County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Pittsylvania County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Pittsylvania County, Va. land surveys (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Prince Edward County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Rockingham County, NC (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Southampton County, Va. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Bodie Historical Southern Families (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - 1787 Census of Va. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Genealogy, Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Genealogy, Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Genealogical societies (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - LDS- Morman Church (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Letters, Libraries (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Maps (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - National Archives (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Virginia State Library and Archives (Box 21, Folder 8)